<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-21T10:28:49-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/_site/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gabriel Sanchez’s writings</title><subtitle>A minimal place for Gabriel Sanchez's writings.</subtitle><author><name>Gabriel Sanchez</name></author><entry><title type="html">Pouring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/18/pouring.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pouring" /><published>2022-02-18T07:46:47-03:00</published><updated>2022-02-18T07:46:47-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/18/pouring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/18/pouring.html">&lt;p&gt;There was nothing to think about at first. Fred felt the rainy season. When the rain lasted a week, Fred shrugged. It was midway through the second week that Fred began to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a Thursday, and the rain had lasted 11 days. Fred, who would never qualify as a loner, noticed that everything in his house had a thin layer of water droplets. The world around him was damp and gray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Fred woke up on Saturday and realized that it was raining, slight despair gripped him for a few moments. Could this be the Flood again? Nah, according to The Book, the world would end in fire. &lt;em&gt;Am I the only one who notices this rain?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existence was suffocating because of the humidity in the air. Everything had a heavy, lifeless feel. Motionless. But the rain continued and dominated Fred’s mind. Not having anyone to share this situation with made it all the more difficult. No one would understand Fred’s concern over mere rain. Just water. Just dry it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred no longer showered. &lt;em&gt;Why if I’m always wet!?&lt;/em&gt; His clothes; the whole house was damp. All the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradually, everything was withering away. The rain, not stormy, fell steadily. Fred spent his days just listening to the rain. No perspective. Unwilling to exist in this gray and wet world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water rose higher and higher. Despair began to take hold of Fred. Is the world turning into a gigantic ocean? Fred felt he was alone. Like always. There was no way out. It was inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Fred didn’t fight much. The natural spasms of a body self-conscious enough to try to save itself occurred, but they weren’t enough. Fred perhaps cried, but the tears mingled with the water that encompassed his entire reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The day started calmly today, but the inhabitants of the Sunnyvale neighborhood woke up to a terrible tragedy: Fred Gates, 28, was found lifeless in his bathtub with signs of drowning. Forensics say he’s been dead for at least 3 days. Fred’s body was found by a resident of the building he lives in who reported a strange smell coming from Fred’s apartment. The police rule out murder and believe it to be a case of drug overdose suicide that culminated in Fred’s accidental drowning when he passed out from too much medicine. Next to the bathtub were several open medicine bottles and a short note. The police did not give details of the note. Fred leaves no family and has no close family members. We were unable to contact any possible friend of Fred to comment on the tragedy. Now, in Weather Forecast, the week will remain as sunny as it has been in the last few days…“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gabriel Sanchez</name></author><summary type="html">Fred starts to worry when what seemed like regular rain never stops.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Patient zero</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/07/patient_zero.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patient zero" /><published>2022-02-07T09:40:01-03:00</published><updated>2022-02-07T09:40:01-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/07/patient_zero</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/07/patient_zero.html">&lt;p&gt;When the virus appeared, people didn’t care so much. They thought it would be an isolated case. There was hypocritical empathy in the air; &lt;em&gt;it will not leave that continent&lt;/em&gt;. People would question facts all the time. The price of technological progress. Distorted information. Conversations about anarchy. Racism. Xenophobia. Things started to take a dark turn when the first cases were reported on other continents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that transmission occurs through contact with infected saliva or blood. Initial symptoms are the common symptoms of a strong infection. High fever, body aches. The final stages include dementia, possible anxiety attacks, and tantrums. Death in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great pyres were burning countless bodies in the open air. Curfews have become lockdowns. People avoided going out on the streets, and those who did were often violent and looting. People who had slowly stocked up on supplies had to venture out into the streets to restock. Gradually, pilgrimage became usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phillipe saw his big luck when he heard the message on the radio. “Research center seeks volunteers to study a vaccine.” Phillipe knew his contribution would be vital. His certainty that his organism was immune came from an event where his infection seemed inevitable. Phillipe wanted to help the world. Phillipe wanted his blood to be studied so that a vaccine would be a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Phillipe was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What started with quizzes and light studies became torture. Patients died as men in lab coats tested different pathogens. Phillipe realized too late that the scientists didn’t want a cure; they just wanted to control the virus. Control the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the last lucid thought of Phillipe who, strapped to a stretcher, had been injected with an aggressive version of the virus. Not even his body could contain the infection. Tears streamed down his expressionless face as his thoughts clouded to the point where Phillipe no longer had any discernment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just one feeling. An insatiable feeling. A will that, for a human being, seems surreal or unhealthy. Hunger. Meat hunger. Hunger for human flesh.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gabriel Sanchez</name></author><summary type="html">Tides seem to turn when Philippe gets news that researchers want volunteers for a vaccine to cure a lethal virus that is plaguing humanity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy forever</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/01/happy_forever.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy forever" /><published>2022-02-01T08:32:01-03:00</published><updated>2022-02-01T08:32:01-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/01/happy_forever</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/02/01/happy_forever.html">&lt;p&gt;At first, Jack tried to avoid those thoughts. &lt;em&gt;Ungodly&lt;/em&gt;. But eventually, Jack succumbed to them. Having a gun at home makes so much sense now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no particular night. Jack just waited for the signal. His family perhaps noticed something eerie, but a couple &lt;em&gt;nothing, babe, I’m good&lt;/em&gt; was enough to dismiss any suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The signal came on a regular night. A very quiet night. Jack got out of bed; prepared the gun. &lt;em&gt;Make it swift. Make it painless.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bang!&lt;/em&gt; One to the head. His other daughter woke up lost. She only had enough time to wonder. &lt;em&gt;Bang!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jack! Where are you!?” Ann said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack’s wife didn’t want to believe that at first. When she saw him with the gun at hand, she had enough time to scream. &lt;em&gt;Bang!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I killed them!” Jack said. He started repeating himself in tears with a hysterical laugh. People in white burst into Jack’s cushioned room. Syringes at hand. He pushed them off, but during his screams, they were able to drug him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no other way, ma’am. We tried everything we could. I know, I know. The procedure is painless, ma’am. Trust me, after the procedure, Jack will be happy forever. He is scheduled for tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gabriel Sanchez</name></author><summary type="html">Jack's decent into madness.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Workaholic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/01/30/workaholic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workaholic" /><published>2022-01-30T11:19:01-03:00</published><updated>2022-01-30T11:19:01-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/01/30/workaholic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/_site/2022/01/30/workaholic.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another half hour and it’s over&lt;/em&gt;. I thought on a typical Friday. The thought of just another low-to-middle-class worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared to leave. Same for the people who work with me at a large table. The long awaited weekend. It is there every week, but we always crave it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough time to barely breathe the air we call pure. The meetings were crazy that Monday. I closed my agenda on purpose to avoid more meetings. Performance depends on pro-activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another weekend. And another. And one more. I just noticed something wrong when I saw my fingers while typing in my office. A mark of what looked like a ring. A wedding ring?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wedding seemed distant to me. How could I have time for marriage with so much work? A CEO needs focus. Meeting now; I’ll think about it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t even see my life go by. Work took over me, I didn’t even see my marriage fall apart; in fact, I didn’t even see my marriage. Was there a wedding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to look outside. Oh well, there is no “outside,” just a fake window with a nice picture to avoid distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Reschedule all meetings for Monday. It’s okay, yeah, don’t worry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to take more care of myself. I left the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rearranging the Friday meetings seemed dumb when I saw the agenda for today, but at least I enjoyed the weekend. I don’t really remember. I don’t remember much outside of work. I don’t remember anything but work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to stay calm as I walked to the exit. I saw some people looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was killing me. Leaving early yesterday accumulated a lot of things. Wait. I went out yesterday and what did I do? Desperate, I hurried to the exit. Everyone looked at me standing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doorman was smiling. A strange smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leaving early again, sir?” he said. “You seem to be looking for something.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t open the main door. I ordered him to open the gate. His crooked smile freaked me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your life is here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality took me like a club to the head. Distorted memories of a life wasted dedicating myself to work. The contacts I accumulated as I moved up the company and the people who disappeared as I was always unavailable. My wife, my daughter, my true friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My death by heart attack. In my office chair, of course. An inevitable fate for someone whose stress was a constant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dead. I died from working too hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolute fear overwhelmed me with the last line I remember from the doorman.
“Nothing fairer than eternity in the environment you love most, sir.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another half hour and it’s over. I thought on a typical Friday. Another half hour for me to enjoy a well-deserved weekend for a low to middle class worker. The day flew by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doorman was strange today, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Welcome once more,” he said with a grim smile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gabriel Sanchez</name></author><summary type="html">Working hard gets a dark tone when you realize you might not be living anymore.</summary></entry></feed>